<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: workflow | Benedikt Wolters]]></title>
  <link href="http://mightyuhu.github.com/blog/categories/workflow/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mightyuhu.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-20T16:50:15+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://mightyuhu.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Benedikt Wolters]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using git stash to cache your pending changes]]></title>
    <link href="http://mightyuhu.github.com/blog/2011/09/26/using-git-stash-to-cache-your-pending-changes/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-26T15:36:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mightyuhu.github.com/blog/2011/09/26/using-git-stash-to-cache-your-pending-changes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is just a quick tip which i stumbled upon this weekend. Let's say you are working on a git branch with a unfinished amount of changes. Now you want to switch branches i.e. to lookup some older/newer value, but you do not want to commit your unfinished piece of work. The solution? <code>git stash</code>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>git stash</h2>

<p>Let's say your Project changes look like this atm:</p>

<p>{% gist 1242067 %231 %}</p>

<p>The Usage is pretty simple just type use git stash:</p>

<p>{% gist 1242067 %232 %}</p>

<p>And your working directory is clean (last commit):</p>

<p>{% gist 1242067 %233 %}</p>

<p>Be aware that git stash also saved the unstaged changes so far. Now you can switch branches and do your stuff...</p>

<p>If you want to reapply your stash just type: <code>git stash apply</code>
By default that would ignore the staging you've done so far, so to also restage your changeset use <code>git stash apply --index</code>
If you have multiple stashes <code>git stash apply</code> will always pick the latest.</p>

<p>{% gist 1242067 gistfile1.txt %}</p>

<p>You can also have multiple stashes and unapply some subset of them. But that goes beyond that blog post.
If you want to learn more just read the wonderful <a href="http://progit.org/book/ch6-3.html">ProGit Book</a> by <a href="http://scottchacon.com/">Scott Chacon</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
