<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Linux | Benedikt Wolters]]></title>
  <link href="http://mightyuhu.github.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mightyuhu.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-07T17:21:47+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://mightyuhu.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Benedikt Wolters]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lubuntu 13.04 and Samsung Series 7 Keyboard Backlight]]></title>
    <link href="http://mightyuhu.github.com/blog/2013/09/05/lubuntu-13-dot-04-and-samsung-series-7-chronos-keyboard-backlight/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T13:28:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mightyuhu.github.com/blog/2013/09/05/lubuntu-13-dot-04-and-samsung-series-7-chronos-keyboard-backlight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% flickr_image 9682918058 z center %}</p>

<p>I' using Lubuntu 13.04 more and more often lately on my Samsung Series 7 Chronos 700Z5A. While the most things worked pretty right out of the box. It took me a while to figure out why the adjustable keyboard backlight FN-Keys were not working. While there are plenty resources available for the Series 9 but no one in particular for Lubuntu and openboxi/i3 i've decided to share the knowledgde with the public and not only with google and the NSA.</p>

<p>The first think i've noticed that the standard installation has already loaded the <code>samsung_labtob</code> kernel module.
You may check that by running
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 check-mod.sh %}</p>

<p>You also can test if the module works by setting a value between 1 and 8 to the backlight driver:
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 echo-brightness %}</p>

<p>Unfortunately the udev mappings were not defined so i had to manually add the following lines to my <code>/lib/udev/keymaps/samsung-other</code>
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 samsung-other %}
and also add the following to the <code>/lib/udev/keymaps/force-release/samsung-other</code>
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 force-release-samsung-other %}
You may have to reload udev by
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 reload-udev%}
and reboot.
After that you can check whether your mappings work by running
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 check-mapping %}
the <code>kbdillumup</code> and <code>kbdillumdown</code> events should appear.</p>

<p>Now the next thing we need to do is bind those keyboard events to an action. In order to allow a script to change the driver values i've setup a init script in <code>/etc/init.d/brightness.sh</code>
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 etc-init.d-brightness %}
and gave it execution rights.
Furthermore, i've added the following line to my <code>/etc/rc.local</code> that executes that script
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 etc-rc.local %}
Then, i wrote a tiny shell script in my home directory <code>/home/bewo/Scripts/backlight.sh</code> that allows me to increment or decrement the current backlight value
{% gist 6444126 backlight.sh %}
In order tu run it without a prefix-path i've created a symbolic link to it
{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 link_script.sh %}
Finally all was left to do is to bind my shell script in OpenBox by adding the following keybinds to my  <code>.config/openbox/lubuntu-rc.xml</code>:</p>

<p>{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 .config-openbox-lubuntu-rc.xml %}</p>

<p>When you're using i3 you can add the following to your <code>.i3/config</code> analogically</p>

<p>{% gist ea52ff46bc5cf9b940f4 .i3-config %}</p>

<p>If that does not work check by running xev if you're bindings trigger the proper X11 events.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
